RIKO PERNANDO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

◆ BANDAR LAMPUNG, INDONESIA

← +62-856-5878-0793

• DETAILS •

Bandar Lampung Indonesia +62-856-5878-0793 pernandoriko3@gmail.com

• LINKS •

<u>Instagram</u>

Linkedin

Facebook

Github

o SKILLS o

Git

MySQL

Node.js

Bootstrap

CSS

HTML

jQuery

React

PHP

JavaScript

Laravel

Vue JS

Svelte

Material UI

HOBBIES

- Gaming(Playstation)
 - Watching Movie
- Reading Book and Blog

PROFILE

I've been a Software Engineer since 2016 with a strong passion to learn new things. I'm familiar with a few JavaScript frameworks and PHP frameworks and developed Web for a production system. Currently, I'm working in <u>bareksa.com</u> as Front-end Engineer.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Frontend Engineer at PT Bareksa Portal Investasi, Jakarta

October 2018 — Present

- Define and develop guidelines to ensure code quality.
- Collaborated with teams to deliver advancements and solutions.
- Worked to build and improve upon tools.
- Improve high quality HTML/CSS/JS code, ensuring codes that i developed are cross-browser and cross-platforms compatible
- Ensuring web products I develop adhere to our company-wide style guide and match the designed user experience.

Web Developer at PT Andaglos Global Teknologi, Bandar Lampung

April 2016 — September 2018

- Built and maintained web application for the accounting platform, hospital platform, etc
- Participated in software design discussions.
- · Problem solved with various stakeholders.
- Effectively managed individual priorities and deadlines.
- Improved software and delivered products under tight time constraints.

★ PROJECT EXPERIENCES

Bareksa Web

I rebuilt the web platform for our company with React Js as the main technology in the front-end.

Bareksa is the first integrated online mutual fund marketplace in Indonesia.

You can see in https://www.bareksa.com

Bareksa Prioritas

Asia's first digital wealth management platform for HNW clients collaboration with an independent investment advisor.

You can see it in https://prioritas.bareksa.com/ or for see screenshot of the platform, you can see in here https://ibb.co/album/5hWZrh

I built this platform with React Js as the main technology in the front-end.

Bareksa For Business

Mutual fund platform for institutional customers. I build the whole front-end, with React as the main technology.

You can see it in http://bisnis.bareksa.com or for see screenshot of the platform, you can see in here https://ibb.co/album/QkpmSx.

Expensify App

Expense manager platform. You can see it in https://appexpensify.herokuapp.com/

Tech Stack: React, Firebase

EDUCATION

Learn React Native, Andaglos Academy, Bandar Lampung

April 2018 — May 2018

Full Stack Web Developer, Pesantren Programmer Ibnu Kosasih, Bandar Lampung

April 2016 — September 2018

Teknik Listrik, SMK N 1 Way Tenong, Lampung Barat

April 2011 — April 2014

COURSES

The Complete React Developer Course (w/ Hooks and Redux), Udemy

October 2021 — October 2021

Membangun API dengan GraphQL, Kode.id

June 2019 — August 2019

Tata Cara Clean Code pada JavaScript, Kode.id

April 2019 — May 2021

Developer: Presentasi dan Public Speaking, Kode.id

January 2020 — March 2020

Full-Stack Web Designer, BWA

January 2021 — March 2021